MARC HOWARD WEINER

Technical Director, Software Engineer, R&D, UX/UI Designer

mhweiner.com linkedin.com/in/mhweiner github.com/mhweiner mhweiner234@gmail.com

Objective

With 15+ years of experience in software engineering and UX/UI design, I have led cross-functional teams that design and build award-winning applications. I enjoy problem solving using research and a pragmatic, iterative approach. I am looking for a challenging opportunity in a collaborative environment in either technical or UX positions.

Skills

Javascript (incl. ES6), PHP7, HTML5/CSS3, Java, C++, Python, Technical Strategy, R&D, Full-Stack development, Process Design, IA, UX/UI Design, Wireframing/Prototyping, Performance Optimization, CI, Build Tooling & Release Engineering, Automated Systems, Scripting, node.js, React, Cordova, git, MySQL/NoSQL, Docker, Linux, Strategic Hiring, Team Building, Cross-functional Team Leadership, Sketch, Invision, Illustrator CC, Photoshop CC

Work Experience

Senior Software Engineer Consultant

Shutterstock, New York, NY

06/2017 - 11/2017

CONTRACT

- Architected and wrote majority of internal service orchestration service
- Worked with other stakeholder teams to understand and gather technical requirements
- Solved performance issues with legacy system and designed performance-driven architecture
- · Led in writing technical documentation and API specification
- Established design patterns throughout the application, including testing procedures and philosophy.
- Tech: node.js REST API w/ express, Behavior Driven Development (BDD) with 100% test coverage

Founder 06/2016 - 04/2017

Ciro, New York, NY

- Founded company aimed at solving communication inefficiencies in development teams (https://ciroapp.com)
- Gathered requirements, conceptualized, and built MVP to prove concept and hypotheses
- Did all Information Architecture, UX/UI design, wireframing, visual design, and full-stack development
- Tech: Fully-responsive, real-time SPA, custom component-based Javascript framework. PHP7 REST API, Docker

Director of Front-End Technology, UX

04/2014 - 05/2016

Advizr, New York, NY

Led the architecture, UX, design, and front-end development of award-winning application from the ground up, with small team and an iterative Agile process. (https://advizr.com)

- Recognized as Best Client Facing Technology of 2015 by FPPad.
- Pre-revenue to over \$2MM/yr within 2 years.
- Led and helped build a small team of developers, freelancers, and managed a creative agency. Made key hires.
- Transitioned company to an iterative Agile development process.
- Led technical strategy, architecture & development of flexible custom component-based Javascript front-end.

02/2013 - 10/2013 Marvel, New York, NY CONTRACT

Led R&D, architecture and front-end development of Marvel.com, one of the first high-traffic, content-rich, fullyresponsive websites.

- Invented and developed new technology which allowed us to post-process sass files, in conjunction with a device detection system to dramatically reduce payload size, while still allowing a single source code.
- Solved major technical challenges such as payload size, performance & optimizations, legacy browser support, mobile optimization, and ad integration.
- Led in key initiatives to ensure front-end team can deliver by deadline. Led meetings, setting standards, methodologies, and process, such as the Responsive Module Library and interactive style guide.
- Tech: Javascript, HTML5/CSS3, PHP

Founder, CTO, Lead Software Engineer, UX Design

01/2001 - 04/2014

Marc H. Weiner Consulting, New York, NY

Led small cross-functional teams deliver wireframes, designs, architecture, full-stack/cross-platform development, technical specifications, R&D, cross-platform development for startups and Fortune 500 companies. Performed BA/ requirement gathering. LAMP stack, custom HTML5/CSS3/Javascript, Cordova, and real-time systems.

Director of User Experience, Senior Software Engineer

08/2012 - 11/2012

Remedy Systems, New York, NY

Full-stack development for medical startup with the goal of preventing hospital readmissions by designing a social network platform for the care team around the patient.

- Led UX and design, and mentored junior UX designer and other developers.
- Helped company transition to Agile process, define objectives and requirements. Sprint planning, led scrum and key meetings.
- TDD, wrote automated unit & integration testing
- Tech: HTML/CSS/Javascript/PHP5.5/Symfony2/Apache/MySQL

Lead Software Engineer

04/2006 - 6/2009

NextEMR, New York NY

Led business analysis, UX, design, and full-stack development of one of the first web-based EMR (Electronic Health Record) application to be certified by CCHIT, with the goal of improving efficiency, transparency, accountability, and overall patient care.

- Successfully acquired in 2009
- · 3rd party integrations with billing software and pharmacy system
- First EMR with integrated task-based load balancing system for employees based on role and workload
- Tech: HTML/CSS/Javascript/AJAX, LAMP stack, HL7

Front-End Web Developer

10/2005 - 01/2006

DigitasLBI, New York, NY

CONTRACT

Developed micro-sites for American Express, Delta, The New York Times, and Time Warner.

Education & Certifications

Private Pilot Certificate (SEL) — Federal Aviation Administration, 2015 Computer Science, Aerospace Engineering — University at Buffalo, Buffalo, NY, 2005